<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Rob's Blog - General</title><link href="https://safuya.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://safuya.net/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://safuya.net/</id><updated>2019-05-22T18:49:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Touch Typing</title><link href="https://safuya.net/touch-typing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-22T18:49:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-22T18:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Robert Hughes</name></author><id>tag:safuya.net,2019-05-22:/touch-typing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't been very active on my blog recently, so I thought I should try to
get back into it with any topic. Lately, I've been trying to work on my touch
typing. After many years of following my own method for typing, I figured it
would be nice to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I haven't been very active on my blog recently, so I thought I should try to
get back into it with any topic. Lately, I've been trying to work on my touch
typing. After many years of following my own method for typing, I figured it
would be nice to do it properly, break those years of bad habits and build up
to a better typing speed than the plateau I'd reached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started working on my touch typing on 12th May, and I've been making sure to
practice for 15 minutes per day. I've managed to complete my goal so far, and
my typing has become more accurate. I also think I've reached and surpassed my
typing speed before this. It is hard to tell because I've only been measuring
my speed with the touch typing methods since starting, so I don't know what my
typing speed was before this switch. I'm now averaging 45 to 55 words per
minute on standard words. I still need practice on symbols, although I am
ahead of my training tools expectations here due to the programming and shell
practice throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest problems I had initially was remembering the pattern for
passwords. I had a period near the end of last week where I couldn't type with
my old habit to enter my passwords, but I had to type very deliberately with
touch typing to get them right. I have now gotten them to a reasonable speed,
and with the amount I get to practice them, I'm sure I'll surpass the old
speed soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it has been helpful to me, and I would recommend programmers spend
time on improving their typing habits.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>